

## **SKILLS**

Frontend development
Micro-frontends
Architecture
Staring projects from scratch
Testing
Infrastructure
Investigation
Backend development

Mentoring Leadership Team organizing Tasks assignment

## CONTACT

P: +48 662 921 496 P: +375 29 212 0592

E: alexsharabayko@gmail.com W: alexsharabayko.github.io

City: Warsaw

## SOCIAL

fb: @alexsharabayko inst: @alexsharabayko github: @alexsharabayko

# ALEX SHARABAYKO

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### **ABOUT**

Hi there! My name is Alexander I have been working as frontend developer since 2013 and I'm still passionate about my job. Usually I participate in bigsize long-term projects but also I have experience with small ones. Familiar with mentoring and team leadership.

I'm able to take care of establishing project or set of projects, its architecture and moving it in needed direction. I also don't mind working on more usual tasks like bug fixing, creating markups, etc.

I also have enough personal and communication skills to understand what and how we need to develop to achieve best user experience and meet business goals.

I have experience in backend as well: I've implemented middle-size servers using Laravel, Strapi. It would be nice to work with BE too.

Except work I like various types of activities from cooking and reading to cycling or boxing. Not a big extreme guy and not a home guy.

You are also can look at my web resume: https://alexsharabayko.github.io/

Open both remote and in-office positions. Currently in Warsaw.

Nice to meet you!

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

## JAVASCRIPT / TYPESCRIPT

Level: advanced

• Vanilla JS, Angular, Rx JS, React JS, Redux, Web Components

# HTML/CSS

Level: advanced

• HTML5, CSS3, Sass/Scss, Styled Components

## **BUNDLERS / INFRASTRUCTURE**

Level: intermediate

• Webpack, Jenkins, Docker, AWS, CI/CD, Unit testing, Storybook

#### BACKAND LANGUAGES

Level: intermediate

• Node js (Express, Strapi), PHP (Laravel), Python

## MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

Level: intermediate

• React Native, Ionic, adaptive/responsive markups



## SKILLS

Frontend development
Micro-frontends
Architecture
Staring projects from scratch
Testing
Infrastructure
Investigation
Backend development

Mentoring Leadership Team organizing Tasks assignment

## CONTACT

P: +48 662 921 496 P: +375 29 212 0592

E: alexsharabayko@gmail.com W: alexsharabayko.github.io

City: Warsaw

## SOCIAL

fb: @alexsharabayko inst: @alexsharabayko github: @alexsharabayko

# ALEX SHARABAYKO

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### LEAD FRONTEND DEVELOPER

IDT Corporation | May 2019 - Current

Tech stack: Angular, React, Web Components, Jenkins, Docker, Sip JS, HTML/SCSS, WebRTC, Redux, Rx JS. Webpack, Node JS

Working as a frontend tech lead and a scrum master on net2phone - a VOIP solution for small/medium size companies.

- Implementation of "micro-frontend" architecture in the product
- Developed common UI library of components which can work with any framework
- Started projects from scratch
- Feature implementations
- Bug fixing
- Team mentoring and leadership
- Scrum mastering
- Working on non-standard tech task like SIP issues, WebRTC or addon for Google Calendar
- Requirements clarification and documentation

## FRONTEND / BACKEND DEVELOPER, CO-FOUNDER

Oh What App | Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

Tech stack: React Native, Strapi, Node JS, Postgres, Firebase

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ohsmmmobile My friends and I were trying to create our own sophisticated app for SMM in Instagram. Minimal goal for me - learning a backend development.

- Participated in frontend development on React Native
- Created the server for this app using Strapi CMS
- Features / UX discussions

### FRONTEND / BACKEND DEVELOPER, CO-FOUNDER

Healthgoing | Mar 2020 - Sep 2021

Tech stack: Angular, RxJS, HTML/Tailwind, Laravel, Stripe, WebRTC, Web sockets, Node JS

https://healthgoing.com/

My friends and I are trying to create solution to connect nutritionists with their customers.

- Started and participated in frontend development on Angular
- Created the server for this app using Laravel framework for PHP
- Features / UX discussions

## SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Exp Capital | Aug 2018 - May 2019

Tech stack: Angular, Ionic

Participated in development of https://capital.com/ and https://currency.com/ as a senior frontend dev.

- Participated in frontend development with Angular and Ionic
- Bug fixing



### SKILLS

Frontend development
Micro-frontends
Architecture
Staring projects from scratch
Testing
Infrastructure
Investigation
Backend development

Mentoring Leadership Team organizing Tasks assignment

## CONTACT

P: +48 662 921 496 P: +375 29 212 0592 E: alexsharabayko@gmail.com W: alexsharabayko.github.io City: Warsaw

# SOCIAL

fb: @alexsharabayko inst: @alexsharabayko github: @alexsharabayko

# ALEX SHARABAYKO

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

MIDDLE / SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Viaden Media / Skywind | Sept 2014 - Jul 2018

Tech stack: Angular, React JS,HTML/CSS/SASS, Angular, Node JS, Electron, Backbone JS, jQuery,

Started as a middle frontend developer. At first helped my team to develop https://www.galabingo.com/ and https://www.galacasino.com/ - fixed bugs, implementing new features on Backbone.

Then participated in development of internal Backoffice using angular and started Electron app from scratch for our customers.

- Participated in frontend development using Backbone, Angular, React
- Bug fixing
- Started Electron / Angular desktop app from scratch
- Feature implementations
- Bug fixing
- Team mentoring

## JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

HiQo Solutions | Jul 2013 - Aug 2014 Tech stack: JS, HTML/CSS, jQuery, Backbone

Starting point of my career. Was member of internship program then worked as junior engineer: fixed bugs, implemented small features for different projects, for example https://www.hiqo-solutions.com

- Participated in frontend development on vanilla JS, jQuery
- Bugs fixing
- Small features implementations

### **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR DEGREE - MATH FACULTY
Belarusian State University | 2010 - 2015

THE COMPLETE NODE.JS DEVELOPER COURSE PYTHON AND DJANGO FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP BUILD A BACKEND REST API WITH PYTHON & DJANGO

Udemy